A Finding Aid to the Frank K. M. Rehn Galleries Records, 1858-1969 (bulk 1919-1968), in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Miscellaneous Records, circa 1920-1968; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 20-21; 0.7 linear feet; Reel 5872)
  - Artwork, A-Z, 1925-1927; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Reel 5872)
    - Unidentified, 1926-1927; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Reel 5872, Frame 77-85)
  - Lists of Paintings, circa 1920-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Reel 5872, Frame 87-725)
  - Names, Addresses, and Telephone Numbers, circa 1920-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 21)
  - Notes about Artists, A - Z, 1940s; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Reel 5872, Frame 729-807)
  - Notes about Paintings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Reel 5872, Frame 809-818)
  - Notes, Miscellaneous, 1919-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Reel 5872, Frame 820-914)
  - Painting Labels, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Reel 5872, Frame 916-918)
  - Writings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Reel 5872, Frame 920-934)
- Photographs, 1871-1966; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 22, 24, and OV 25; 1.0 linear feet; Reel 5872)
  Photographs of people include both artists represented by Rehn Galleries and several not affiliated with the gallery. A 1945 group portrait of gallery artists includes Alexander Brook, Charles Burchfield, John Carroll, John Clancy, Edward Hopper, Morris Kantor, Peppino Mangravite, Reginald Marsh, Henry Mattson, George Picken, Henry Varnum Poor, Frank K. M. Rehn, Eugene Speicher, Bradley Walker Tomlin, and Franklin C. Watkins. Another group portrait is of the 27th Carnegie International Jury of Award and American Committee of Selection. Noticeably absent are likenesses of Frank K. M. Rehn and John C. Clancy. Photographs of works of art are by Rehn Galleries' artists and others.
  Reginald Marsh's photographs consist of family and personal photographs that were either given to Rehn Galleries or perhaps borrowed for research at the time of his memorial exhibition. Views of Marsh from early childhood through old age consist of studio portraits, informal photographs, and publicity shots of Marsh at work; also included are photographs of family and friends, and a small family album, with few individuals identified. Other photographs are of Marsh's childhood drawings executed between ages 4 and 8, and buildings, including two identified as mother's church and father's church.
  Miscellaneous subjects are a dog and exhibitions. Exhibition installation views consist of an unidentified exhibition, circa 1923, probably Rehn Galleries, probably at 5 West 50th Street, and two views of the "Rehn Group," possibly at the Carnegie Institute, 1920.
  This series is arranged into 4 subseries:
  6.1: People, 1917-1966, undated
  6.2: Works of Art, circa 1905, 1960-1964, undated
  6.3: Reginald Marsh's Photographs, 1871-1952, undated
  6.4: Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1923, 1928, 1950, undated
  - People, 1917-1966; undated; 6.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Ames, A., undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 939-940)
    - Carroll, John and Pinky, circa 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 942-943)
    - Edelstein, Babette, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 944-945)
    - Hartman, Rosella, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 947)
    - Hopper, Edward, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 949-950)
    - Marsh, Reginald, Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872)
      Scope and Contents
      Scanned with 6.3: Reginald Marsh's Photographs
    - Mattson, Henry, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 952-953)
    - Meyer, Herbert, Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872)
    - Mintz, Raymond (?), 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 955-956)
    - Little, Dr. Charles S., Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872)
      Scanned with Roosevelt, Gov. Franklin D. and Dr. Charles S. Little
    - Rehn, Margarete, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 958-959)
    - Roosevelt, Governor Franklin D. and Dr. Charles S. Little (at Letchworth Village, Thiells, N. Y.), 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 961-966)
    - Rosen, Charles, 1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 968)
    - Wilder, Ruth, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 970-971)
    - Unknown (includes "Spike"), 1917; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 973-976)
    - Artists of the Rehn Galleries (Peter A. Juley and Son, Photographers), 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 978-979)
      Materials also scanned on Reel 1817, frames 1329-1330
    - 27th Carnegie International Exhibition, Jury of Award and American Committee of Selection, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 981)
      Oversized material housed in Box 24
  - Works of Art, circa 1905; 1960-1964; undated; 6.2; Archival Resource Key
    - Bellows, George, circa 1905; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 984-987)
    - Blagden, Allen, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 989)
    - Brook, Alexander, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22)
    - Brown, Gwyneth King, Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872)
      Scanned with King, Gwyneth
    - Burchfield, Charles E. (includes family collection of Mr. and Mrs. Walter Fillin, Rockville Centre, NY), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 992-994)
    - Busch, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 996)
    - Chapin, James, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 998-1002)
    - Corbino, Jon, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22)
    - Crane, Bruce, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1006-1007)
    - Crespi, Danielle, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1009-1010)
    - Dasburg, Andrew, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1012-1019)
    - Driggs, Elsie, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1021-1022)
    - Edelstein, Babette, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1024-1031)
    - Fromentin, Eugene, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1033-1034)
    - Gatch, Elsie Driggs, Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872)
      Scanned with Driggs, Elsie
    - Giles, Howard, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1036)
    - Griffin, Walter, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1038)
    - Gross, Sidney, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1040-1049)
    - Harshe, Robert B., undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1051-1064)
    - Hartman, Rosella, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1066-1069)
    - Hassam, Childe, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1071)
    - Henri, Robert, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1073-1113)
    - Hopper, Edward, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1115-1133)
    - Hubbard, Earl Wade, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1135-1136)
    - Johnson, Eastman, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1138-1141)
    - Kaufman, Irving, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1143-1152)
    - Kimball, Yeffe, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22)
    - King, Gwyneth, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1155-1156)
    - Kozlow, Richard, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22)
    - Lawson, Ernest, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22)
    - Lie, Jonas, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1160-1161)
    - Luks, George, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1163-1165)
    - MacIver, Ian T., undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22)
    - Martin, Homer D., undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1175)
    - Marsh, Reginald, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1168-1173)
    - Mattson, Henry, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22)
    - McFee, Henry Lee, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1178-1185)
    - Melchers, Gari, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1187)
    - Murphy, J. Francis, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1189-1190)
    - Picken, George, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1192-1193)
    - Poor, Henry Varnum, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1195-1196)
    - Rehn, F.K.M., [Sr.], Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1198)
    - Rosen, Charles, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1203-1204)
    - Russo, Alexander, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1206)
    - Schweider, Arthur, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1208-1209)
    - Slatin, Yeffe Kimball, Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872)
      With Kimball, Yeffe
    - Soyer, Raphael, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1211)
    - Speicher, Eugene, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1213-1293)
    - Strater, Henry, 1960-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1295-1300)
    - Templeton, Robert, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1302-1307)
    - Thayer, Abbott H., undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1309)
    - Trebilcock, Paul, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1311-1329)
    - Tucker, Allen, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1331-1340)
    - Tucker, Richard Derby, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 22)
    - Twachtman, John H., undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1343-1344)
    - Watkins, Franklin C., undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1346-1347)
    - Wilder, Ruth, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1353-1356)
    - Weir, J. Alden, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1349-1351)
    - Unidentified, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1358-1378)
  - Reginald Marsh's Photographs, 1871-1952; undated; 6.3; Archival Resource Key
    - Reginald Marsh, 1900-1947; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1381-1427)
      Oversized material housed in Box 24 and OV 25
    - Family Album, 1912-1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1431-1473)
    - Family and Friends, 1871-1952; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1475-1496)
    - Meyer, Herbert [?], undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1498-1507)
    - Childhood Drawings, 1902-1906; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1509-1516)
    - Buildings (mother's church, father's church, and unidentified), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1518-1522)
    - Oversized Photos, Reginald Marsh, 1900-1947; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Reel 5872)
      Oversized materials scanned with Reel 5872, frames 1381-1427
    - Oversized Photos, Reginald Marsh, 1900-1947; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 25, Reel 5872)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1923-1928; 1950; undated; 6.4; Archival Resource Key
    The Carnegie International Exhibition photograph includes Ernest Lawson, Homer Saint-Gaudens, Colin Gill, Anto Carte, Jonas Lie, Robert Spencer, Mahonri Young, Rockwell Kent, and Guillaume Lerolle.
    - Dog, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22)
    - Exhibitions, circa 1923; 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Reel 5872, Frame 1526-1529)
    - Carnegie International Exhibition, Jury of Award and American Committee of Selection, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Reel 5872)
      Oversized material scanned with Reel 5872, frame 981
    - Rehn, F.K.M. [Sr.], undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Reel 5872)
      2 copies; autographed by 30 artists; oversized material scanned with Reel 5872, frame 1198